<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: association, | The Official Rentobo Blog | Rental Property Software]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/categories/association-/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-09T17:47:23-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rentobo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Renting Property? Join a Landlord Association]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/renting-property-join-a-landlord-association/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/renting-property-join-a-landlord-association</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are a lot of DIY landlords out there. Some property owners got into the business as a way to generate some extra cushion on their monthly expenses; others wanted to replace their job. Many times, a sole proprietor wants to run their business in peace, without brokers or outside property management firms getting in the way. No matter what the circumstances of your business as a landlord; it is always good to join a good landlord association in your area. Here are a few reasons why you should.</p>

<h3>Stay Up To Date On Laws and Restrictions</h3>

<p>Many conflicts between landlords and their tenants occurred not as a result of neglect, but of misinformation. As a landlord, misinformation can mean disaster for your business. However, even if you actively educate yourself, certain new rules and regulations in your market can slip through the cracks. A great way to avoid this dilemma is to join an association.</p>

<p>The benefit here is obvious. You have a community of people as opposed to one, all with the same purpose of adhering to the laws and restrictions of their markets. Many sources are better than one when it comes to protecting your business by being knowledgeable.</p>

<p><strong>Related: <a href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/importance-of-up-to-date-leases/">The Importance of Up-To-Date Leases and Agreements</a></strong></p>

<h3>Learn About New Trends</h3>

<p>The rental industry is always changing. How people find and sign apartments and leases is different from how how did it 20 years ago, and being part of an association will help you keep tabs on what’s going on.</p>

<p>In addition to knowing your laws, it can be beneficial to follow known best practices in your market. For instance, if you charge $80 per applicant, but the typical application runs closer to $40 in your area, it is better to have this information rather than alienate yourself from additional prospects.</p>

<h3>Networking</h3>

<p>A great way to connect with people that can actually help your business is by being a part of a community with the same agenda as you. In a landlord association, the ‘salesmen’ are going to be limited, so as a landlord, you can network freely and without limitation. Some of the best partnerships occur when people that had no intention of working with someone else suddenly put their heads together.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
