<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Marketing | The Official Rentobo Blog | Rental Property Software]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/categories/marketing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-09T17:50:48-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rentobo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Benefits of Syndicating Your Listing]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/benefits-of-listing-syndication/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/benefits-of-listing-syndication</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Marketing a rental listing is about getting exposure, which will draw prospects to your unit. When generating interest for your listing, a lot of property owners will settle for “good enough.” Unfortunately, if you settle for promoting your unit “just on craigslist,” for example, you really limit your audience. Here we present the case for syndicating your listings across multiple search sites.</p>

<h3>It's Faster</h3>

<p>Most property owners agree that displaying their listings in more than one place is beneficial. However, manually visiting each website individually to post their listings is hard to manage and time consuming. With multiple listings and properties, the problem is magnified greatly.</p>

<p>So if your time is precious, like all professionals and property owners, you’ve probably wished there was a better way. When you syndicate your listing using a syndication platform, such as <a href="http://www.rentobo.com">Rentobo</a>, you can actually submit your listing to multiple search sites at the same time. This will save you a lot of time and give you more time to work on other areas of your business.</p>

<h3>It’s Efficient</h3>

<p>In the real estate and rental markets, the term <a href="http://www.thefreedictionary.com/Syndication">syndication</a> has taken on a whole new meaning. When you choose to market your listing using a syndication platform such as Rentobo, you choose to let a multitude of real estate rental search sites, such as Zillow, Apartable, and Lovely, promote a common interest by displaying your listings. This is truly a powerful thing when you think about it.</p>

<p>Each one of these sites generate thousands of new eyes a day in most markets. Granted, some of those site visitors of Zillow may have come from craigslist. However, if a rental prospect has viewed your listing on multiple listing sites, they are more likely to click on it. Now, instead of posting on one site over and over again, you are able to provide multiple impressions through one piece of effort. That’s efficient.</p>

<h3>It’s Easy</h3>

<p>At Rentobo, we have made it incredibly easy to syndicate your listings. In just a few seconds, you can submit your listing to the most popular rental search sites on the web, simultaneously. This is how it works:</p>

<p>Once you have created a listing using Rentobo, you can manage your marketing efforts by selecting the<strong> Promote tab.</strong></p>

<p>Simply scroll to the bottom, and you will see a list of syndication partners to choose from. After that, just select the boxes corresponding to the sites you want to submit to, and click ‘Save Syndication Options.’
That’s it! Once your selections have been saved, Rentobo will create and submit listings to the partners you have selected, where they will appear within 24-48 hours.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
