<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: advice | The Official Rentobo Blog | Rental Property Software]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/categories/advice/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-09T17:37:29-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rentobo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guest Post: How to Manage Your Bills Properly as a Tenant]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/how-to-properly-manage-your-bills/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/how-to-properly-manage-your-bills</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://oblog.rentobo.com/images/image01.png" width="315" height="185">
Do you dread opening your mailbox? Does that stack of bills pile up every month until it becomes an unmanageable heap? An apartment comes with a multitude of different expenses. Besides paying your rent each month, you most likely have to pay your utility bills, which include gas, electric, heat, cable, internet and any other expenses you are responsible for in your building.</p>

<p>Every month I have to keep up-to-date on my utility bills as well as my credit card bill, tuition payment, and rent. Keeping everything in order and paid on time took awhile to get a handle on. Let’s just say I had to pay a few late fees! Here are some tips on how to manage these monthly bills and make it to the end of the month without any extra fees.</p>

<h3>1. Stay Organized</h3>

<p>My problem is keeping everything organized. With so many bills to pay each month, the biggest challenge I face is just keeping everything in order. Once I started organizing all of my bills and keeping track of what I owed, my life became infinitely easier and my checking account a little heavier. My biggest piece of advice would be to stay organized and always know what you owe.</p>

<h3>2. Process Your Mail Right Away</h3>

<p>I used to let my mail sit for days (and to be truthful, weeks) when I brought it in from the mailbox. One time my mail piled so high that I accidentally threw my electric bill away with a bunch of old take-out menus and forgot to pay it that month. Now I go through my mail daily and separate the bills from the junk mail.</p>

<h3>3. Keep Your Bills in a Designated Place</h3>

<p>It’s easier to stay organized when everything is in one place. I keep mine in the top drawer of my desk and at the end of the month when the bills need to be paid I put them in a basket by the front door so I never forget them on my way out in the morning.</p>

<h3>4. Designate a Specific Time to Pay Your Bills</h3>

<p>Procrastination never helped me in school and it certainly hasn’t helped when it comes to paying bills. I’ve learned that if I set time aside each month, I’m less stressed out. I usually set time aside on the weekend when I have less going on to pay my bills and review my bank balance.</p>

<h3>5. Pay Your Bills Online</h3>

<p>Almost every utility company and bank offers you the ability to pay your bills online. Paying online is more convenient and saves you the trip of having to walk to the mailbox. If you’re a tenant, go one step further and see if your <a href="http://www.williampaid.com/collect-rent-online">landlord</a> will let you <a href="http://www.williampaid.com/pay-rent-online">pay your rent online</a>. It’s one less bill you will have to worry about keeping track of at the end the of the month. As a landlord, Rentobo is in the process of creating a way for you to accept payments online. You can stay up to date by <a href="http://www.rentobo.com">joining our mailing list</a>.</p>

<p><em>Submitted by WilliamPaid.com. WilliamPaid lets renters &amp; roomies pay rent online, automatically, with more flexibility and it's FREE. Users can also build credit with each rent payment.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The importance of responding quickly to maintenance requests]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/responding-quickly-to-maintenance-requests/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/responding-quickly-to-maintenance-requests</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Whether you manage your basement suite, a single property or a number of rental units, responding quickly to maintenance requests from your tenants is important. One of the primary reasons why people choose to live in a rental property is the freedom from responsibility for repairs, maintenance and upkeep - from the tenant's perspective, that's your job. Doing repairs in a timely manner can have a big impact on the bottom line of your rental business, affecting everything from the total cost of the repair to your tenant turnover rates.</p>

<h3>Quality Tenants Expect Customer Service</h3>

<p>Great tenants are in great demand (and in most cases, they know it.) This means that even in markets with extremely low vacancy rates, top-tier tenants who are willing to pay a premium for their rental unit expect their landlord or property manager to respond quickly to maintenance issues.</p>

<p><strong>See also:</strong> <a href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/what-to-do-when/">How to fill a tough rental vacancy</a></p>

<p>Even if the problem seems minor to you, from the perspective of your tenant, the longer they need to wait for a repair to be completed, the more time they have to reconsider if they want to continue living in your unit. Failing to respond quickly to maintenance requests is the rental equivalent to leaving someone on hold; the longer the customer needs to wait, the more agitated they'll become. Put them on hold long enough and chances are good they'll hang up and take their money elsewhere.</p>

<h3>A Quick Response Can Prevent Bigger Problems</h3>

<p>Unless you happen to have a tenant who is skilled in building maintenance, you need to do a hands-on assessment of your property as soon as your tenant contacts you with a repair request. Often tenants can't (or won't) bother to investigate a problem with their unit. Again, the tenants expect you to do that. Responding quickly to a call from your tenant can save you the hassle and costs of a major repair. After all, that tiny leak in the ceiling could be the sign of a pipe that's ready to burst, or that plug that stopped working could be the result of rodents eating away at your electrical wiring.</p>

<p>By providing your tenants with a quick response to a call for repairs, you can help keep your paying tenants happy (which will improve your retention rates) and catch small problems before they turn into major maintenance headaches, saving you both time and money.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
