<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: rent payments | The Official Rentobo Blog | Rental Property Software]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/categories/rent-payments/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-09T17:37:29-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rentobo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Renovating Your Personal Rental Property Worth It?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/Is-renovating-your-personal-rental-property-worth-it/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/Is-renovating-your-personal-rental-property-worth-it</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Landlords who want to attract the best tenants and achieve low turnover rates know the importance of regular property maintenance, however, most property owners have difficulty deciding if they should invest in a major renovation on their personal rental property. When renting property, it can be tempting to simply leave your rental units alone, but doing the right renovations can maintain the value of your investment. You can also attract higher rent payments from stable tenants who are willing to pay a premium for a modern, updated rental apartment or home.</p>

<h3>When Rental Property Renovations Make Sense</h3>

<p>Doing renovations on personal rental property makes sense if you are looking to increase the rent payments, if you plan on selling the unit soon or you want to make major changes to attract more tenants. For example, if you consistently have trouble renting out a studio (bachelor) apartment, it might make sense to convert that unit into a one-bedroom to attract tenants who like the idea of having a traditional-style bedroom.</p>

<p>See Also: <a href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/affordable-tips-for-sprucing-up-your-rental/">The affordable way to renovate when renting property.</a></p>

<h3>Research Before You Renovate</h3>

<p>Before you decide to undertake any renovations, take the time to do some market research; check your area classified ads to see what style of units seem to be in high demand and which ones look difficult to rent out. Often small low-cost renovations, such as adding in-suite laundry, installing a dishwasher or upgrading the bathroom can allow you to command higher rents for your personal rental property.</p>

<p>Another key factor in deciding whether or not personal rental property renovations are worth it is the time it will take you to recover your costs - for example, if you invest $3000 to improve the bathroom, how much will you need to raise the monthly rent to cover that cost (and will the market bear the higher rent)?</p>

<h3>Timing Your Rental Renovations</h3>

<p>The best time to upgrade your personal rental property is when you are between tenants - trying to do major renovations while the unit is occupied is a recipe for disaster. Anything that you or your contractors do that might be perceived as diminishing the habitability of the unit (such as temporary disruptions to the water or electrical service) can put you at risk of legal trouble from your current tenant.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
