<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: rental brokerage tips | The Official Rentobo Blog | Rental Property Software]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/categories/rental-brokerage-tips/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-09T17:47:23-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rentobo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Tips for Brokering a Relocating Tenant]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/three-tips-for-brokering-a-relocating-tenant/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-16T11:17:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/three-tips-for-brokering-a-relocating-tenant</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Not all prospects are local. Everyday, people across the country and abroad search for and sign a lease on a new apartment. Many times the lease is signed before the tenant has had a chance to view the unit. Some people have concerns with this process, also known as “blind leasing,” so here are some tips on how to avoid the pitfalls and make the transition easy for yourself and your prospective tenant.</p>

<h3>Clarity is crucial in your listing</h3>

<p>If you want your listing to appeal to as many buyers as possible, you need to include some critical details. This means going beyond the usual language of bed/bath and whether the countertops are granite. While this information is important for everyone, relocating prospects are more concerned with information about the neighborhood, school district and proximity to points of interest. After all, the actual unit is only part of the overall living experience for your tenant, and a well-informed prospect will be happier with their decision.</p>

<h3>Good pictures of actual unit</h3>

<p>Many listings, particularly ones in larger buildings, will contain pictures of a unit ‘similar’ to the actual one. If someone reaches out to you about your listing, take the extra step to send them more accurate pictures. These images can be a substitute when the tenant can’t actually visit the unit. Make sure the images are clear and include descriptions. If you do this right, a prospective tenant can have a clear visual of the place they may move into, which will make their decision easier.</p>

<h3>Communicate well</h3>

<p>The importance of communication is magnified when your prospect can’t meet with you in person. So make sure that you keep you communicate well with your prospects, whether it’s via email, phone or both. The average out-of-state tenant is going to have more questions during the process, so it’s good practice to ensure that you are easy to reach. Again, this is good customer service, which can go a long way in such a competitive market.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
