<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: single-family housing | The Official Rentobo Blog | Rental Property Software]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/categories/single-family-housing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-09T17:47:23-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rentobo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Case For Single-Family Rental Investment ]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/single-family-rental-investment/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/single-family-rental-investment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last year, 367,000 single-family homes were sold in the US. This number is the highest since 2009, and nearly a 20% <a href="http://www.valueline.com/Markets/Commentary.aspx?id=14076">jump from 2011</a>. This is good news to participants in the housing market, but what are some of the economic drivers behind some of these purchases?</p>

<p>Investment firms such as <a href="http://www.blackstone.com/">Blackstone Group</a> and <a href="http://data.cnbc.com/quotes/SBY">Silver Bay Realty Trust</a> have allocated billions of dollars of capital towards the single-family market, with a focus on distressed and/or bank-owned foreclosure properties. The purpose of this investment is to buy in bulk, renovate if necessary, and rent out their inventory while the housing market rebounds. Jade Rahmani, an analyst with KBW, says “By some accounts, $6-9 billion has been raised or committed, suggesting potential acquisitions of 40,000-90,000 properties.” This accounts for roughly 15% of unsold REO (real estate owned) <a href="http://www.cnbc.com/id/100366417">housing units</a>.</p>

<p>Traditionally, a lot of real estate investment firms <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424127887324034804578346800317118568.html">had shied away from the single family market (paywall)</a> due to the complexities of managing geographically dispersed properties. We're developing Rentobo's next-generation <a href="http://www.rentobo.com">rental property management software platform</a> with this in mind; whether you're a single family landlord or a large organization with hundreds or thousands of units under management, we're building the best experience possible for finding and connecting with the best tenants for your property.</p>

<p>That is a big number that actually helps the rental market more than the housing market. Houses are being purchased, but the a large number of their owners are renting them out instead of actually living in them. Non-investment homeownership in the <a href="http://www.census.gov/housing/hvs/files/qtr412/q412press.pdf">US is down to 65%</a>, which is the lowest it has been in 15 years. Consider these factors:</p>

<ul>
<li>When people lose their homes to foreclosures, <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/kenrapoza/2012/04/04/how-single-family-home-investing-can-save-the-housing-market/">60% end up renting a single-family home</a>, with another 23% renting an apartment.</li>
<li>Over the last five years, foreclosures have caused over <a href="http://www.realestateeconomywatch.com/2012/04/single-family-rentals-now-exceed-multifamily/">3 million homeowners</a> and put them into the rental market.</li>
<li>There are an estimated <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/kenrapoza/2012/04/04/how-single-family-home-investing-can-save-the-housing-market/2/">6.3 million Generation Y</a> aspiring renters that currently live with their friends or at home while they financially establish themselves in a tough job market. These kids are expected to enter the rental market within the next 5 years.</li>
<li><a href="http://makinsensebabe.com/number-of-new-us-single-family-homes-sales-fell-in-december-2012-while-home-prices-rose-so-basically-nobody-can-afford-a-home/">22% of borrowers are are “underwater”</a> whereas a healthy economy would put that number at around 5%. For some of these people, without a lot of help, they will soon enter the rental market as well.</li>
<li>The U.S. has solid demographics for homeownership, but new housing supply is <a href="http://www.blackstone.com/news-views/blackstone-blog/blackstone-creates-national-single-family-rental-home-platform">63% below the historical average.</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Indicators such as these are perhaps the reason why <a href="http://www.cnbc.com/id/46538421/Warren_Buffett_on_CNBC_I_d_Buy_Up_A_Couple_Hundred_Thousand_Single_Family_Homes_If_I_Could">Warren Buffett</a> said “I’d buy up a couple thousand single-family homes” if he found it reasonable to do so. He believes that if you do buy a single-family home in which to live, make sure you get a 30 year mortgage (to keep your monthly cash expenses minimized) and refinance when rates are better.</p>

<p>For a family, a single-family unit is an attractive rental option. Families prefer to live in single-family units as opposed to large multi-family buildings. For property owners, these residents tend to be more stable and stay longer than a typical young single tenant.</p>

<p>What all of this means is that now is a better time than ever to consider renting out a single-family homes and becoming a landlord. Rates are low, the demand is not only high but inevitable, and in most markets, current mortgage payments are <a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/monthly-rent-vs-monthly-mortgage-payment-2013-1">lower than rental premiums</a> (which means money in your pocket).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
