<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: online rental applications | The Official Rentobo Blog | Rental Property Software]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/categories/online-rental-applications/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-09T17:37:29-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rentobo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Benefits of Online Rental Applications]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/benefits-of-online-rental-applications/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-08T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/benefits-of-online-rental-applications</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The digital age has made various aspects of the property rental industry easier for businesses to maintain their day-to-day job. This includes the rental application. Online rental applications help streamline the application portion of the rental process and provide various benefits that paper versions cannot.</p>

<h3>Time Saver</h3>

<p>The amount of time you save by switching to online rental applications is the number one reason why property managers choose this option. Online applications allow the potential resident to quickly find out if they are eligible as a renter. After the credit and background checks come back, you can approve the resident and allow them to log in to the website and sign the apartment lease in a matter of minutes. Since electronic signatures are now considered as legally binding as written ones, the tenant can easily sign all required documents from the comfort of their home.</p>

<h3>Ease of Use</h3>

<p>Internet usage is more popular now than ever, and potential renters regularly search online for available rental properties. Online rental applications allow potential renters to fill out and send in the application as soon as they find your listing online. Offering the convenience of online rental applications puts you ahead of the competition and increases the amount of applications you receive. In addition, your listing will reach a greater number of tech-savvy, young tenants who know you are the type of landlord they can easily work with.</p>

<h3>Better Organization and Less Clutter</h3>

<p>Electronic applications drastically reduce the amount of paper flow you have to deal with. Rather than wading through a filing cabinet packed with individual leases, instantly pull the desired lease up on your computer. Also, you can easily make changes to your lease and make it available to residents immediately.</p>

<h3>Getting Started</h3>

<p>Getting started with online rental applications is a relatively simple process with various online resources designed to help property owners new to electronic applications. Typically, you can choose from a wide array of pre-made templates for the application or customize your very own. Another option is to upload the current application you are using and make it available electronically for potential renters.</p>

<p>Computers, the Internet and technology in general have greatly simplified and improved the way potential tenants find properties. By implementing electronic applications, you ensure your business won't miss out on all the benefits provided by online applications.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Update: Improved Photos, Tenant Handouts]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/announcing-new-rentobocom-site-enhancements-w/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/announcing-new-rentobocom-site-enhancements-w</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Team at Rentobo would like to thank everyone in advance for a tremendous
amount of awesome and helpful feedback! We have been working very hard to
improve our site, and make it more valuable for our users. The Team has been
listening to your needs, wants and desires, and have responded with these
updates. More to come!</p>

<h2>Larger Photos</h2>

<p>In response to user feedback we have increased the size of the photos on the
Rentobo listing page. We have also improved our strategy for processing and
resizing uploaded photos to ensure they are displayed as consistently as
possible on partner sites. </p>

<h3>Photo Uploads Made Simple</h3>

<p>Our users can now upload photos using a simple drag and drop feature.  This
means you can literally drag your chosen photos from your desktop folder into
our upload box, and the photos will automatically upload.  You can load one at a
time, or highlight and drag several photos at once!</p>

<p>We have also made it easier for users to rearrange uploaded photos for each
listing.  We have employed a dragging feature which allows you to drag the
photos you have already uploaded into their appropriate spots.  This allows you
to display your photos in any order, without restriction.</p>

<p><img src="http://oblog.rentobo.com/images/42095304-RentObo_Photo_Reorder.png"></p>

<h3>Print and Go Tenant Handouts</h3>

<p>Users can now easily download a tenant handout, print and distribute them at
showings and open houses in place of paper applications.  The handouts convert
to PDF format for easy printing. Tenant Handouts guide potential tenants back to
Rentobo to apply and help tenants to remember your listing after a day of
apartment hunting.</p>

<p><img src="http://oblog.rentobo.com/images/42095314-RentObo_Tenant_Handout.png"></p>

<h3>Introducing Apartable</h3>

<p>We are happy to introduce a new syndication partner for listing
promotion: <a href="http://www.apartable.com" title="Apartable.com">Apartable.com.</a> </p>

<p>Rentobo listings will be displayed on Apartable with a special badge to let
users know they can apply for the listing online with Rentobo.</p>

<h3>Other Improvements</h3>

<p>This release also includes a number of bugfixes and improvements to existing
functionality including but not limited to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Improved email notifications (with more information and links to review
relevant information)</li>
<li>Better reliability when posting to Craigslist by integrating listing
descriptions copied from MS Word</li>
<li>Added open house times to Craigslist posts (when applicable)</li>
<li>Simplified tenant signup when applying for a listing</li>
<li>Added additional scheduling options for open houses shorter than 30 minutes</li>
</ul>


<p>Again, our team is working around the clock to make Rentobo.com the most
efficient, user-friendly way to find and sign new tenants for your rental
property. If there are any questions or concerns you have while using our site,
feel free to let us know at:</p>

<p><a href="mailto:support@rentobo.com">support@rentobo.com</a> (We like compliments too!)</p>

<p>-The Team At Rentobo</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apartment Applications and Leases]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/84233293/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-05T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/84233293</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-MWOmMBZr2dg/TgA6fCFPbcI/AAAAAAAARQ0/qriitvEYbB4/s1600/worried+Eyes01.jpg" width="262" height="400"></p>

<p>Being an individual owner is not easy. Before you think about renting out your
place there is the mess of regulations to comply with, and in some
cities <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/1998/03/01/realestate/for-the-small-landlord-all-problems-are-big.html?pagewanted=all&amp;src=pm">upwards of 20 governmental agencies administer these regulations</a>. For
some it can seem a lonely task, but you might be surprised how many other small
landlords there are out there. Individuals own two thirds of the nation’s 26
million unsubsidized rental units, and over 80 percent of structures with four
units or less.</p>

<p>Renting out an apartment is not easy either. Owners must worry about property
maintenance, figuring out what rent to charge, advertising the property,
screening tenants, and preparing and signing a lease. In San Francisco, vacancy
rates are so low that owners reportedly are receiving up to <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/12/02/us/in-apartment-hunt-looking-isnt-free.html?_r=1&amp;src=recg">250 applications per listing</a>.
That’s a lot of paper to manage! Even before receiving these
applications, owners have to be careful how they advertise the property, and
what questions they ask prospective tenants, either on the application or in
person. For starters, the <a href="http://hud.gov/fairhousing">Federal Fair Housing Act</a> makes it illegal to
discriminate based on a host of factors - race, color, national origin,
religion, sex, family status, or disability. But there are state and city laws
as well. Additionally, brokers maintain lists of <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/03/29/nyregion/29appraisal.html">no-no phrases</a>. Is your
place a “bachelor pad” or a “fisherman’s retreat,” in a “traditional
neighborhood,” “perfect for shares or families”? You might think twice before
advertising your unit using any of those phrases.</p>

<p>So what’s the solution? What can you do to make the process easier? Rentobo
simplifies the entire process. Using Rentobo you can post your ad to Craigslist
with as many photos as you would like, drive prospective tenants to fill out an
application and do the credit check online without worrying about all the legal
mumbo-jumbo, and finally have the tenant sign the lease online.</p>

<p>The next time 200 people come to your apartment and want to rent, you can
welcome them all, and not have to worry about managing all those paper
applications!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
