<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: rental marketing | The Official Rentobo Blog | Rental Property Software]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/categories/rental-marketing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-09T17:50:48-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rentobo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Rentobo To Market Your Rental Property]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/using-rentobo-to-market/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/using-rentobo-to-market</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Craigslist is one of the 10 highest ranking pages on the internet in the US, according to <a href="http://www.alexa.com/siteinfo/craigslist.org">alexa.com</a>. Naturally, when building Rentobo, we decided to make it as convenient as possible to post your listing there. But craigslist is only the beginning. Market analysts have determined that 70% or more of new renters begin their searches <a href="http://www.mynewplace.com/press-releases/magnetic-marketing-apartment-owners-can-snare-the-lions-share-of-renters-by-ramping-up-their-online-initiatives">online</a>. With that in mind, we built our promotions tool to capture as much of that market, as efficiently as possible.</p>

<h3>How it works</h3>

<p>The days of needing to be computer savvy to market your property are over. With Rentobo, even a novice can now market online by <a href="http://www.rentobo.com/howitworks">using it to promote their listings</a>.</p>

<p>Using Rentobo, you can promote to craigslist and a host of other major rental search sites simultaneously and with just a few clicks. Unlike posting directly to craigslist, you can upload as many photos as you’d like. Once you have created a listing, Rentobo will automatically save it into your management dashboard in case you need to use it at a later date.</p>

<p><strong>Related: <a href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/Rentobo-makes-it-easier-for-you-to-post-to-craigslist/">Rentobo makes it even easier to post to craigslist</a></strong></p>

<h3>Accepting applications</h3>

<p>When you create and post a listing with Rentobo, prospective tenants can submit applications online. This way, you can receive information such as employment history, salary information and rental history before you ever speak with them on the phone or see them in person. A lot of landlords and brokers enjoy having this information before moving forward with a full credit and background screening.</p>

<p>*We are also in the process of integrating full background and credit screening with Rentobo. If you would like to learn more and participate in our upcoming, limited beta program for this feature, click <a href="http://www.rentobo.com/tenant_screening">here</a>.</p>

<h3>Getting started</h3>

<p>Getting started is easy. Visit <a href="http://www.rentobo.com">Rentobo.com</a> and enter the address for your property on our home page. Our quick-start wizard will allow you to create a listing in just a few short minutes. The best part is that setting up and promoting your listing on Rentobo is free!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[When To Offer Rental Concessions]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/when-to-offer-concessions/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/when-to-offer-concessions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While property owners in high demand areas have less difficulty recruiting tenants, investors who own rental units in areas with high vacancy rates may need to offer rental concessions to both current and prospective tenants. If your rental property is located in an area where there are more vacancies than there are qualified tenants, providing perks to your renters can make the difference between maintaining your rental cash flow or having your units sit empty.</p>

<h3>What Concessions Should You Offer?</h3>

<p>A Los Angeles landlord recently made headlines with her unique rental concession; Sandy Zalegens, a property investor and animal rescue advocate, recently offered new tenants a $150 discount on their monthly $950 rent on the condition that they adopt Big Louie, a 80-pound Pit Bull dog who <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/08/17/pitbulls-landlord-discounts-rent_n_1790737.html">needed a home.</a></p>

<p><strong>See Also:</strong> <a href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/ethical-challenges-of-being-a-landlord/">Ethical Challenges of Being a Landlord</a></p>

<p>Although Zalegens' concession did help her find a great tenant for her unit, most property owners cannot (and likely should not) be quite that creative when it comes to providing incentives to attract tenants. Nevertheless, it might not hurt to think ‘outside of the box’ when it comes to offering concessions. Consider what you can offer, focusing first on low-cost ideas such as allowing pets, providing free parking or including cable TV service. Enticing tenants by including utilities is another popular perk, as it saves them the hassle of activating their own utility accounts while the cost to the landlord is usually justified.</p>

<h3>Concessions Can Help Improve Retention Rates</h3>

<p>Rental concessions aren't just for new tenants --- by offering "loyalty rewards" to stable tenants, you will cut your vacancy rates as well as eliminate the costs associated with tenant turnover. Ongoing retention incentives can include deals like "pay 12 months, get the 13th month rent-free," and discounted rates on laundry tokens and cards (if you offer a tenant laundry room). You can also research bulk discounts on sports tickets, fitness center passes and grocery gift cards to give as "thank you" gifts to stable tenants.</p>

<p>The type of concessions you offer will depend on the demands of both your market and your tenants. The bottom line is that it is better to offer rental concessions for continued cash-flow than to have your rental properties remain vacant.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What to Do When You Can’t Fill Your Vacancies]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/what-to-do-when/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-05T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/what-to-do-when</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Managing rental properties can be like running any other business. There are ups and downs in the market, and sometimes a landlord is forced to make adjustments. Life is easy when you have an abundance of eager prospects, but what do you do when interest dries up? Here are some simple fixes that can get your vacancy filled.</p>

<h3>Always assess what you should be charging</h3>

<p>One thing to remember is that a unit is only as valuable as someone is willing to pay for it. While you might not want your rental unit to be a steal-of-a-deal, you don’t want to price yourself out of the competition. If you have trouble finding a tenant, reassess the prices of similar property in your area. Be prepared to lower your rent if the data is convincing enough. If you stay competitive, people will notice.</p>

<h3>Encourage lease renewals</h3>

<p>Keeping your tenants happy increases the likelihood they will renew their lease, sparing you the time and cost associated with finding new tenants. The costs associated with turning over a rental property can be significant (lost rent, marketing/broker’s fees, maintenance, etc.) and <a href="http://www.naahq.org/blog/lists/Posts/Post.aspx?ID=222">can possibly exceed $4,000</a> according to an analysis by the National Apartment Association. Timely responses to maintenance requests and convenient perks like online rental payments are ways to improve tenant satisfaction and your bottom line.</p>

<h3>Consider an inexpensive update</h3>

<p>If your rent is competitive, eventually people will view it. Pay attention to what they say. If the kitchen cabinets are in rough shape, get them fixed. If the carpet is truly repulsive, sometimes a steamvac and shampoo isn’t enough. Change it out. In a situation where your prospects have a choice, they will be looking for a place they can call home, not just rent that is easy on the wallet.</p>

<h3>Offer incentives for referrals</h3>

<p>Sometimes the best way to keep your vacancies filled is to have your current tenants fill vacancies for you. Prospects tend to trust people that they know, so incentivize your renters for finding your next tenant. To do this, ask your tenants if they know someone that may be interested, and that you would be willing to provide a finder’s fee for helping you out. This may amount to a discount on their final month’s rent, or a gift card. If you have a positive relationship with your tenant, they are likely to give you a good referral.</p>

<h3>Pay for utilities</h3>

<p>Sometimes it might be an insignificant cost that keeps your prospects from renting your property. Often a prospective tenant will enjoy not having to pay for utilities like electric or gas. If the amount is too unreasonable, consider paying for a predetermined amount of time, say six months or a year. This will ensure that you keep your expenses at bay in the case of a long term tenant.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
