<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: leases | The Official Rentobo Blog | Rental Property Software]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/categories/leases/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-09T17:37:29-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rentobo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Importance of Up-To-Date Leases and Agreements]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/importance-of-up-to-date-leases/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/importance-of-up-to-date-leases</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In most cities, both local and state jurisdictions regulate important property management issues such as collecting and returning security deposits, rental rate increases and the terms of the tenancy. Landlords need to maintain current leases and rental agreements for all their units in order to qualify for protection under landlord-tenant laws as well as to protect them against any hassles that can arise during the tenancy.</p>

<h3>The Basics of Rental Leases and Agreements</h3>

<p>Property management can be a complex business - landlords need to deal with both financial issues (collecting rent) and human rights issues (such as anti-discrimination laws). While many successful, long-term landlord-tenant relationships are based on nothing more than a simple handshake, unless there is a compelling reason to skip the paperwork it's always wise to get the rental terms in writing.</p>

<h3>What Can Go Wrong</h3>

<p>In the absence of a current rental agreement or an up-to-date lease, tenant complications or opportunistic scammers can wreak havoc on your property management business. Most tenants are decent, honest people, but you should take steps to protect yourself from professional scammers. There are some <a href="http://www.massrealestatelawblog.com/2012/02/19/massachusetts-landlords-be-aware-of-the-professional-tenant/">“professional tenants”</a> who are skilled at gaming the system by manipulating the rental laws to their advantage, causing their property owners and managers a great deal of grief and monetary loss.</p>

<p>For example, if you don't have a current, written lease, how can you prove the terms of the tenancy should you wind up in a legal battle? Unsavory tenants have been known to make wild claims against unsuspecting landlords in order to skip out on their rent, avoid paying for damages, or worse yet, to make a financial claim for damages against their landlord. A current rental agreement protects landlords and tenants by ensuring that all the terms of the tenancy are in writing. Everything related to the tenancy (particularly the financial details) should be covered in a lease or separate rider/addendum, such as the pet policy, amount and due date of rent and details about the security deposit and future rent increases.</p>

<p>By keeping up-to-date rental agreements and leases on file for all your rental properties, you can set expectations with your tenants, protect yourself and your business in the event that something goes wrong, and reduce your chances of falling victim to scams.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
