<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: new | The Official Rentobo Blog | Rental Property Software]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/categories/new/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-09T17:47:23-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rentobo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[4 Tips For New Landlords]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/4-tips-for-new-landlords/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/4-tips-for-new-landlords</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So you have taken the plunge, and become a new landlord! Maybe you decided to rent out a spare bedroom in your house, or you have acquired your first rental property. Being a landlord is no cakewalk, so hopefully you’ve done your research before taking the plunge. Just in case, here are some checklist items to make sure your business gets started on the right foot.</p>

<h3>Join A Landlord Association</h3>

<p>Many new landlords are in business for themselves---by themselves. If this is you, joining an association <a href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/renting-property-join-a-landlord-association/">can have many benefits</a>. You can stay up to date on the local and national laws, news, and the best practices in your market. You can get invaluable insights from more veteran property owners. You can get the scoop on which vendors to use, and which ones to avoid. For example, there are a lot of different associations throughout Chicagoland and the state of Illinois, and a listing of these organizations can be found <a href="http://www.thelpa.com/lpa/associations/illinois.html">here</a>.</p>

<h3>Decide How Much You’re Willing To DIY</h3>

<p>Being a landlord can be a very hands on or automated business depending on how you manage it. Many property owners will go so far as handling maintenance requests by themselves! However, if you aren’t a professional handyman, you need to figure out how you’re going to quickly and efficiently handle repairs. We talk about the <a href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/responding-quickly-to-maintenance-requests/">importance of handling requests well</a>, and with the right system in place, you will have happier renters and a more profitable business.</p>

<h3>Realize That You Might Get A Bad Renter</h3>

<p>Even the best property owners and managers will have a few renters that are less than ideal. The most common violation that you will face will be late or unpaid rent. Most renters have good intentions when they enter into a lease agreement, but financial situations change, and not everyone is <a href="http://money.cnn.com/2011/05/24/news/economy/americans_lack_emergency_funds/index.htm">prepared for them</a>. We would also recommend you come up with a set policy for noise disturbances and property costs beyond normal wear and tear on your unit.</p>

<h3>Use Rentobo To Find Your First Renters</h3>

<p>Rentobo is a great resource for finding your next renter, whether you are an industry novice or pro. Our simple to use tool will allow you to create a listing and promote your property to craigslist and other major rental search sites simultaneously. Once prospects decide that they are interested, <a href="http://www.rentobo.com">Rentobo</a> allows you to accept applications from them online. Our screening feature (currently in beta) enables you to receive full credit reports complete with scores and criminal background history.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
