<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: maintenance | The Official Rentobo Blog | Rental Property Software]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/categories/maintenance/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-09T17:37:29-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rentobo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The importance of responding quickly to maintenance requests]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/responding-quickly-to-maintenance-requests/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/responding-quickly-to-maintenance-requests</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Whether you manage your basement suite, a single property or a number of rental units, responding quickly to maintenance requests from your tenants is important. One of the primary reasons why people choose to live in a rental property is the freedom from responsibility for repairs, maintenance and upkeep - from the tenant's perspective, that's your job. Doing repairs in a timely manner can have a big impact on the bottom line of your rental business, affecting everything from the total cost of the repair to your tenant turnover rates.</p>

<h3>Quality Tenants Expect Customer Service</h3>

<p>Great tenants are in great demand (and in most cases, they know it.) This means that even in markets with extremely low vacancy rates, top-tier tenants who are willing to pay a premium for their rental unit expect their landlord or property manager to respond quickly to maintenance issues.</p>

<p><strong>See also:</strong> <a href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/what-to-do-when/">How to fill a tough rental vacancy</a></p>

<p>Even if the problem seems minor to you, from the perspective of your tenant, the longer they need to wait for a repair to be completed, the more time they have to reconsider if they want to continue living in your unit. Failing to respond quickly to maintenance requests is the rental equivalent to leaving someone on hold; the longer the customer needs to wait, the more agitated they'll become. Put them on hold long enough and chances are good they'll hang up and take their money elsewhere.</p>

<h3>A Quick Response Can Prevent Bigger Problems</h3>

<p>Unless you happen to have a tenant who is skilled in building maintenance, you need to do a hands-on assessment of your property as soon as your tenant contacts you with a repair request. Often tenants can't (or won't) bother to investigate a problem with their unit. Again, the tenants expect you to do that. Responding quickly to a call from your tenant can save you the hassle and costs of a major repair. After all, that tiny leak in the ceiling could be the sign of a pipe that's ready to burst, or that plug that stopped working could be the result of rodents eating away at your electrical wiring.</p>

<p>By providing your tenants with a quick response to a call for repairs, you can help keep your paying tenants happy (which will improve your retention rates) and catch small problems before they turn into major maintenance headaches, saving you both time and money.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
