<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: advice, | The Official Rentobo Blog | Rental Property Software]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/categories/advice-/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-09T17:50:48-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rentobo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Benefits of Syndicating Your Listing]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/benefits-of-listing-syndication/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/benefits-of-listing-syndication</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Marketing a rental listing is about getting exposure, which will draw prospects to your unit. When generating interest for your listing, a lot of property owners will settle for “good enough.” Unfortunately, if you settle for promoting your unit “just on craigslist,” for example, you really limit your audience. Here we present the case for syndicating your listings across multiple search sites.</p>

<h3>It's Faster</h3>

<p>Most property owners agree that displaying their listings in more than one place is beneficial. However, manually visiting each website individually to post their listings is hard to manage and time consuming. With multiple listings and properties, the problem is magnified greatly.</p>

<p>So if your time is precious, like all professionals and property owners, you’ve probably wished there was a better way. When you syndicate your listing using a syndication platform, such as <a href="http://www.rentobo.com">Rentobo</a>, you can actually submit your listing to multiple search sites at the same time. This will save you a lot of time and give you more time to work on other areas of your business.</p>

<h3>It’s Efficient</h3>

<p>In the real estate and rental markets, the term <a href="http://www.thefreedictionary.com/Syndication">syndication</a> has taken on a whole new meaning. When you choose to market your listing using a syndication platform such as Rentobo, you choose to let a multitude of real estate rental search sites, such as Zillow, Apartable, and Lovely, promote a common interest by displaying your listings. This is truly a powerful thing when you think about it.</p>

<p>Each one of these sites generate thousands of new eyes a day in most markets. Granted, some of those site visitors of Zillow may have come from craigslist. However, if a rental prospect has viewed your listing on multiple listing sites, they are more likely to click on it. Now, instead of posting on one site over and over again, you are able to provide multiple impressions through one piece of effort. That’s efficient.</p>

<h3>It’s Easy</h3>

<p>At Rentobo, we have made it incredibly easy to syndicate your listings. In just a few seconds, you can submit your listing to the most popular rental search sites on the web, simultaneously. This is how it works:</p>

<p>Once you have created a listing using Rentobo, you can manage your marketing efforts by selecting the<strong> Promote tab.</strong></p>

<p>Simply scroll to the bottom, and you will see a list of syndication partners to choose from. After that, just select the boxes corresponding to the sites you want to submit to, and click ‘Save Syndication Options.’
That’s it! Once your selections have been saved, Rentobo will create and submit listings to the partners you have selected, where they will appear within 24-48 hours.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[4 Tips For New Landlords]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/4-tips-for-new-landlords/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/4-tips-for-new-landlords</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So you have taken the plunge, and become a new landlord! Maybe you decided to rent out a spare bedroom in your house, or you have acquired your first rental property. Being a landlord is no cakewalk, so hopefully you’ve done your research before taking the plunge. Just in case, here are some checklist items to make sure your business gets started on the right foot.</p>

<h3>Join A Landlord Association</h3>

<p>Many new landlords are in business for themselves---by themselves. If this is you, joining an association <a href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/renting-property-join-a-landlord-association/">can have many benefits</a>. You can stay up to date on the local and national laws, news, and the best practices in your market. You can get invaluable insights from more veteran property owners. You can get the scoop on which vendors to use, and which ones to avoid. For example, there are a lot of different associations throughout Chicagoland and the state of Illinois, and a listing of these organizations can be found <a href="http://www.thelpa.com/lpa/associations/illinois.html">here</a>.</p>

<h3>Decide How Much You’re Willing To DIY</h3>

<p>Being a landlord can be a very hands on or automated business depending on how you manage it. Many property owners will go so far as handling maintenance requests by themselves! However, if you aren’t a professional handyman, you need to figure out how you’re going to quickly and efficiently handle repairs. We talk about the <a href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/responding-quickly-to-maintenance-requests/">importance of handling requests well</a>, and with the right system in place, you will have happier renters and a more profitable business.</p>

<h3>Realize That You Might Get A Bad Renter</h3>

<p>Even the best property owners and managers will have a few renters that are less than ideal. The most common violation that you will face will be late or unpaid rent. Most renters have good intentions when they enter into a lease agreement, but financial situations change, and not everyone is <a href="http://money.cnn.com/2011/05/24/news/economy/americans_lack_emergency_funds/index.htm">prepared for them</a>. We would also recommend you come up with a set policy for noise disturbances and property costs beyond normal wear and tear on your unit.</p>

<h3>Use Rentobo To Find Your First Renters</h3>

<p>Rentobo is a great resource for finding your next renter, whether you are an industry novice or pro. Our simple to use tool will allow you to create a listing and promote your property to craigslist and other major rental search sites simultaneously. Once prospects decide that they are interested, <a href="http://www.rentobo.com">Rentobo</a> allows you to accept applications from them online. Our screening feature (currently in beta) enables you to receive full credit reports complete with scores and criminal background history.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Renting Property? Join a Landlord Association]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/renting-property-join-a-landlord-association/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/renting-property-join-a-landlord-association</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are a lot of DIY landlords out there. Some property owners got into the business as a way to generate some extra cushion on their monthly expenses; others wanted to replace their job. Many times, a sole proprietor wants to run their business in peace, without brokers or outside property management firms getting in the way. No matter what the circumstances of your business as a landlord; it is always good to join a good landlord association in your area. Here are a few reasons why you should.</p>

<h3>Stay Up To Date On Laws and Restrictions</h3>

<p>Many conflicts between landlords and their tenants occurred not as a result of neglect, but of misinformation. As a landlord, misinformation can mean disaster for your business. However, even if you actively educate yourself, certain new rules and regulations in your market can slip through the cracks. A great way to avoid this dilemma is to join an association.</p>

<p>The benefit here is obvious. You have a community of people as opposed to one, all with the same purpose of adhering to the laws and restrictions of their markets. Many sources are better than one when it comes to protecting your business by being knowledgeable.</p>

<p><strong>Related: <a href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/importance-of-up-to-date-leases/">The Importance of Up-To-Date Leases and Agreements</a></strong></p>

<h3>Learn About New Trends</h3>

<p>The rental industry is always changing. How people find and sign apartments and leases is different from how how did it 20 years ago, and being part of an association will help you keep tabs on what’s going on.</p>

<p>In addition to knowing your laws, it can be beneficial to follow known best practices in your market. For instance, if you charge $80 per applicant, but the typical application runs closer to $40 in your area, it is better to have this information rather than alienate yourself from additional prospects.</p>

<h3>Networking</h3>

<p>A great way to connect with people that can actually help your business is by being a part of a community with the same agenda as you. In a landlord association, the ‘salesmen’ are going to be limited, so as a landlord, you can network freely and without limitation. Some of the best partnerships occur when people that had no intention of working with someone else suddenly put their heads together.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Your Rental Property Up To Code?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/is-your-rental-property-up-to-code/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/is-your-rental-property-up-to-code</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>No tenant should have to wonder whether or not they live in a safe building. However, there are countless stories which prove that not all rental property is safe. A common issue is that many <a href="http://the-accidental-landlord.com/">“accidental landlords”</a> aren’t educated on what makes a building up to code, which can lead to problems down the road. Also, municipalities across the country are having <a href="http://realestate.msn.com/article.aspx?cp-documentid=20171382">trouble keeping up</a> with routine health, safety and fire inspections which only adds to the problem. You should check your local jurisdiction for the most up-to-date laws, but safety should never be an option, so here are some ways to get started.</p>

<h3>Check for obvious fire hazards</h3>

<p>The most common household disaster is <a href="http://www.redcross.org/news/article/Home-Fires-Biggest-Disaster-Threat-in-US">due to fire</a>. Again, check your local jurisdiction, but some common issues to look for include:</p>

<ul>
<li>Lack of a sufficient fire extinguisher</li>
<li>Bad or faulty electric wiring</li>
<li>Lack of a working smoke detector</li>
<li>Objects that obstuct or block emergency exits</li>
</ul>


<p>Fire prevention is often the job of both the tenant and the landlord. The best way to ensure people are being safe is to educate them. To do this, provide your new/current tenants with a simple pamphlet from your local fire department on how to stay safe.</p>

<p><strong>See Also:</strong> <a href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/why-tenants-should-get-renters-insurance/">Why Tenant's Should Have Renter's Insurance</a></p>

<h3>Have a professional take a look</h3>

<p>Very few property owners or managers are properly qualified to inspect a property. Rather than banking on a routine inspection, be proactive---<em>especially</em> if your tenants start to complain. To the untrained, it can be difficult to tell if a crack on the side of the building is cosmetic or dangerous. Also, a good inspector can give you a timeline for when something may need to be updated or replaced, so you can plan ahead. Many disasters and lawsuits can be avoided if you don’t neglect the safety of your property by spending the extra money for a proper inspection.</p>

<h3>Make sure renovations are completed by a professional</h3>

<p>The reasons for this should be obvious. If you’ve ever watched the show <a href="http://www.hgtv.com/holmes-inspection/show/index.html">Holmes Inspection</a>, you will have gotten a glimpse of the pitfalls of a bad home installation or inspection. Rather than potentially throwing your money down the drain, make sure that the vendor you choose is proven and trustworthy. Don’t know where to start? <a href="http://www.angieslist.com">Angie’s List</a>, a vendor review service, and <a href="http://www.buildzoom.com">BuildZoom</a>, a locator service for general contractors, are great resources for finding the right company to get the job done.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
