<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: building | The Official Rentobo Blog | Rental Property Software]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/categories/building/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-09T17:47:23-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rentobo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Your Rental Property Up To Code?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/is-your-rental-property-up-to-code/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/is-your-rental-property-up-to-code</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>No tenant should have to wonder whether or not they live in a safe building. However, there are countless stories which prove that not all rental property is safe. A common issue is that many <a href="http://the-accidental-landlord.com/">“accidental landlords”</a> aren’t educated on what makes a building up to code, which can lead to problems down the road. Also, municipalities across the country are having <a href="http://realestate.msn.com/article.aspx?cp-documentid=20171382">trouble keeping up</a> with routine health, safety and fire inspections which only adds to the problem. You should check your local jurisdiction for the most up-to-date laws, but safety should never be an option, so here are some ways to get started.</p>

<h3>Check for obvious fire hazards</h3>

<p>The most common household disaster is <a href="http://www.redcross.org/news/article/Home-Fires-Biggest-Disaster-Threat-in-US">due to fire</a>. Again, check your local jurisdiction, but some common issues to look for include:</p>

<ul>
<li>Lack of a sufficient fire extinguisher</li>
<li>Bad or faulty electric wiring</li>
<li>Lack of a working smoke detector</li>
<li>Objects that obstuct or block emergency exits</li>
</ul>


<p>Fire prevention is often the job of both the tenant and the landlord. The best way to ensure people are being safe is to educate them. To do this, provide your new/current tenants with a simple pamphlet from your local fire department on how to stay safe.</p>

<p><strong>See Also:</strong> <a href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/why-tenants-should-get-renters-insurance/">Why Tenant's Should Have Renter's Insurance</a></p>

<h3>Have a professional take a look</h3>

<p>Very few property owners or managers are properly qualified to inspect a property. Rather than banking on a routine inspection, be proactive---<em>especially</em> if your tenants start to complain. To the untrained, it can be difficult to tell if a crack on the side of the building is cosmetic or dangerous. Also, a good inspector can give you a timeline for when something may need to be updated or replaced, so you can plan ahead. Many disasters and lawsuits can be avoided if you don’t neglect the safety of your property by spending the extra money for a proper inspection.</p>

<h3>Make sure renovations are completed by a professional</h3>

<p>The reasons for this should be obvious. If you’ve ever watched the show <a href="http://www.hgtv.com/holmes-inspection/show/index.html">Holmes Inspection</a>, you will have gotten a glimpse of the pitfalls of a bad home installation or inspection. Rather than potentially throwing your money down the drain, make sure that the vendor you choose is proven and trustworthy. Don’t know where to start? <a href="http://www.angieslist.com">Angie’s List</a>, a vendor review service, and <a href="http://www.buildzoom.com">BuildZoom</a>, a locator service for general contractors, are great resources for finding the right company to get the job done.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
