<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Renovation | The Official Rentobo Blog | Rental Property Software]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/categories/renovation/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-09T17:50:48-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rentobo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Affordable Tips for Sprucing up Your Rental]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/affordable-tips-for-sprucing-up-your-rental/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-05T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/affordable-tips-for-sprucing-up-your-rental</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A dull property can make it more difficult to find a good tenant. However, for many landlords, updating your rental property can be a daunting task. Not all of us are designers or decorators, and sometimes you just don't know where to start.   Fortunately, there are many low-cost things you can do to make your property more attractive to prospective tenants. Here are some tips to get you started.</p>

<h3>Focus on the kitchen and bath first</h3>

<p>The kitchen and the bathroom are the two most important rooms in your unit. Prospects tend to care about them the most, and they provide the most bang for your buck when you update them. If you're on a budget, the proper approach is to <em>update</em> not <em>modernize</em>.</p>

<p>In other words, don't spend too much money on a more beautiful alternative, when a cheaper option can get the job done. For instance, bathroom tile can run as low as $1 a sheet or as high as $100 a square foot. In most cases, the cheaper option will still give your bath a fresh vibe that prospects will enjoy.</p>

<p><strong>See Also:</strong> <a href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/5-critical-steps-to-make-your-rental-listing/">5 Critical Steps To Make Your Listing Stand Out</a></p>

<h3>New paint, new look</h3>

<p>A fresh coat of paint can do wonders for a bland-looking unit. With that said, the actual task of painting can be time consuming and stressful if you get carried away. There are a couple simple solutions to this dilemma:</p>

<ol>
<li>Select a color that is neutral and stick with that color throughout the unit.</li>
<li>Allow your prospective tenant to paint the unit themselves.</li>
</ol>


<p>The second option can be a huge selling point for your property. Prospective tenants love to visualize their potential new space, and the ability to paint will get their imaginative juices flowing.</p>

<h3>Small changes, big impressions</h3>

<p>If you have a bit of decorator in you, you can still be very budget conscious when updating your unit. Think of small fixes that will leave a big visual impression. Instead of changing your entire cabinet, switch out the knobs and handles. Update that old brass faucet with a polished stainless steel. Attach a new showerhead in the bathrooms.</p>

<p>In some cases, the originality of your fixtures can actually be a selling point. In this case, you can take them off, polish them properly (check out <a href="http://www.hgtv.com">HGTV</a> or <a href="http://www.doityourself.com">DIY</a> for tips on how to this,) and reattach them. Again, it isn't difficult to make a big impact on a space with simple, eye-catching updates.</p>

<p>The best way to approach a property update is to get multiple perspectives. If prospective tenants come to look at your property, pay attention to their feedback. A helpful broker may be willing to give you some tips as well. With a better perspective, you can apply our tips as mentioned to update your unit without breaking the bank.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
