<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Market | The Official Rentobo Blog | Rental Property Software]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/categories/market/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-09T17:50:48-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rentobo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Tenants Should Get Renter's Insurance]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/why-tenants-should-get-renters-insurance/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/why-tenants-should-get-renters-insurance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Homeowner’s insurance is required by any mortgagee and will cover the property itself, any outbuildings as well as the contents of the structure. Landlord’s insurance is required as well, and on top of the building and such being covered; the landlord will also be protected against lawsuits that may occur due to an accident on the property. However, what many tenants do not know is that landlord’s insurance does not cover their personal possessions. Unfortunately, when disasters occur, this lack of coverage can be a real shock to tenants. If this piece of information isn’t compelling enough, here are some other reasons why every tenant should obtain renter’s insurance.</p>

<h3>It protects your belongings</h3>

<p>As a tenant the most compelling and obvious reason for you to be insured is that it will protect your belongings. Landlord’s insurance will not. Policies differ as to whether they offer replacement coverage, which would pay the full cost of replacing an item, or whether the check is mailed out based off of current cash value. In other words, that $1,000 TV that you purchased 6-7 years ago at retail may get assessed and paid at a few hundred dollars instead of the full amount, depending on your coverage.</p>

<p>A good renter’s insurance policy will cover a tenant for burglary as well as something more disastrous such as a fire or flood.</p>

<h3>It prevents liability</h3>

<p>Say one of your guests (or a plumber) trips over an extension cord in your unit, and breaks his ankle. If you get sued and you don’t have insurance, the odds are going to be stacked against you. If the guest trips on his way up the stairs, the landlord would potentially be liable. But because things such as furniture, extension cords and electronics are your property, you are legally obligated to cover those losses.</p>

<p>Many renters are under the impression that if someone is injured in their unit, they will be covered by the landlord’s insurance. This could explain why <a href="http://abcnews.go.com/Business/survey-shows-renters-insurance/story?id=18685618#.UYlU1bWHv-s">two-thirds of renters</a> do not have insurance. If such a scenario occurs and you have renter’s insurance, the typical policy will cover any court award up to a <a href="http://abcnews.go.com/Business/survey-shows-renters-insurance/story?id=18685618#.UYlU1bWHv-s">$100,000 limit.</a></p>

<h3>It’s inexpensive</h3>

<p>Perhaps the most surprising thing about insuring your rental possessions is that it is inexpensive. The average renter’s policy only costs about <a href="http://abcnews.go.com/Business/survey-shows-renters-insurance/story?id=18685618#.UYlU1bWHv-s">$185 a year</a>. You can get $50,000 worth of coverage for about <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/01/29/realestate/getting-started-a-word-to-the-wise-renter-insurance.html?_r=1&amp;">$300 a year</a>. Many policies will include some type of initial deductible should you need to file a claim, and cover any reasonable expenses thereafter. Some companies will also offer a discount should you bundle auto insurance with your policy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
