<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: online tenant screening | The Official Rentobo Blog | Rental Property Software]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/categories/online-tenant-screening/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-09T17:37:29-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rentobo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Tenant Screening is Important]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/why-tenant-screening-is-important/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/why-tenant-screening-is-important</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a landlord, there can be many reasons as to taking a lax approach to screening tenants. But it is better to be safe than sorry. Some property owners, particularly the ones with smaller portfolios, tend to be more relaxed until <em>after</em> they’ve been bitten by a bad tenant or two. Here are some of the reasons why you should always screen a tenant properly <em>before</em> you pay the consequence.</p>

<h3>Past Evictions</h3>

<p>While a standard rental agreement requires that a potential tenant provides photo ID, proves their US residency status, and passes a criminal background, eviction and credit check, many landlords will accept the photo ID and residency status as "good enough" without finishing the entire screening process. Which is to say, they may not even check to see if a tenant has had an eviction.</p>

<p>Evictions are definitely a red flag, as they clearly show that at one point in time the tenant was legally required to vacate their residence. This can spell trouble down the line, especially if the potential tenant has had more than one eviction. By obtaining a credit report and eviction screening, the landlord will have the opportunity to discuss the past eviction with the potential tenant and make an informed decision based on the information they receive. This is a much better alternative to learning the hard way that a tenant isn't who they claim to be.</p>

<h3>Criminal Background Checks</h3>

<p>Criminal background checks are also very important when it comes to potential tenants. Once again, it is ultimately up to the landlord to make the final decision, but learning of a potential tenant's past criminal history can definitely be a deciding factor. If their criminal background check shows a history of theft or vandalism, they may not be the best candidate for tenancy. By learning beforehand, landlords can make their final decision based on facts rather than on instinct, saving themselves from potential trouble down the line.</p>

<p><strong><em>See Also:</em></strong> <a href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/importance-of-up-to-date-leases/">The Importance of Up-To-Date Leases</a></p>

<h3>A Proper Denial Letter</h3>

<p> Additionally, by obtaining the required reports, landlords can send a denial letter based on specific information that they found during the background investigation. If a landlord denies a tenant based on something that is not clearly stated in the tenant qualifications section of the application, they could find themselves in violation of the Fair Housing Act.</p>

<h3>Take the Extra Steps</h3>

<p>While taking the extra steps to follow through on background and credit checks may seem unnecessary to landlords if they have an overall good feeling about their potential tenant, it is always best to follow the rental procedure step by step. This way everyone has their bases covered, and if all goes well, both parties can look forward to a successful landlord/tenant relationship.</p>

<h3>How To Get Started</h3>

<p><a href="http://www.rentobo.com">Rentobo</a> is committed to making it simple for you find a quality tenant for your unit. We are currently in the process of integrating a full screening process into our platform.  If you would like to learn more, or participate in the beta release of this program, <a href="http://www.rentobo.com/tenant_screening">click here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
