<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: landlord tips | The Official Rentobo Blog | Rental Property Software]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/categories/landlord-tips/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-09T17:50:48-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rentobo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ethical Challenges of Being a Landlord]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/ethical-challenges-of-being-a-landlord/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-25T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/ethical-challenges-of-being-a-landlord</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the most important things in running a business successfully is to stick to a code of ethics.
Being a landlord is no different. Even if you have had bad experiences in the past,
making ethical decisions is not an option.  In the long run, sticking to a code
of ethics will help you to earn the trust of your tenants and allow you to run
your rental business more smoothly. Here are some ways in which you can make
sure you’re complying with both the law and proper landlord ethics.</p>

<h3>Properly screen applicants by judging them with the exact same standards.</h3>

<p>You might be tempted to ‘trust your instincts’ while screening a tenant. This is
a no-no for ethical AND legal reasons. Whether you are a new landlord or you
have been in business for 30+ years, rejecting a tenant because of appearance,
familial status or employment is against the law. Always be up-to-date and
comply with Fair Housing and Discrimination Laws. Use full credit, background
and reference checks to select your tenants without bias.</p>

<h3>Don’t get carried away with fees and charges.</h3>

<p>Sure, owning and managing a rental property can get expensive, but the tenant
shouldn’t be the only one incurring those costs. It is the landlord’s duty and
responsibility to maintain the rental property. Any increases in rent, deposits
and amenity fees should be reasonable and competitive with the properties in
your area. In today’s market, it is easy to spot a landlord that just wants to
make a quick buck. A rental property with better prices will retain more tenants
for longer periods of time. This will more than likely mean more income for you
in the long-term.</p>

<h3>Make sure you stick to building and habitability codes.</h3>

<p>You can protect yourself and more importantly, your tenants by being
knowledgeable about and sticking to building and habitability codes. This is
especially necessary when conducting maintenance fixes. Building standards, like
electrical wiring and plumbing, tend to get updated over time. Make sure you
know about these changes and hire licensed professionals to make the proper
updates. Some landlords may be tempted to spend less on a quick-fix, but if the
building isn’t kept to standard, tenants aren’t safe and you could get into
legal trouble. Also, it’s unethical.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
