<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: rental market | The Official Rentobo Blog | Rental Property Software]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/categories/rental-market/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-09T17:50:48-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rentobo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Importance of Up-To-Date Leases and Agreements]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/importance-of-up-to-date-leases/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/importance-of-up-to-date-leases</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In most cities, both local and state jurisdictions regulate important property management issues such as collecting and returning security deposits, rental rate increases and the terms of the tenancy. Landlords need to maintain current leases and rental agreements for all their units in order to qualify for protection under landlord-tenant laws as well as to protect them against any hassles that can arise during the tenancy.</p>

<h3>The Basics of Rental Leases and Agreements</h3>

<p>Property management can be a complex business - landlords need to deal with both financial issues (collecting rent) and human rights issues (such as anti-discrimination laws). While many successful, long-term landlord-tenant relationships are based on nothing more than a simple handshake, unless there is a compelling reason to skip the paperwork it's always wise to get the rental terms in writing.</p>

<h3>What Can Go Wrong</h3>

<p>In the absence of a current rental agreement or an up-to-date lease, tenant complications or opportunistic scammers can wreak havoc on your property management business. Most tenants are decent, honest people, but you should take steps to protect yourself from professional scammers. There are some <a href="http://www.massrealestatelawblog.com/2012/02/19/massachusetts-landlords-be-aware-of-the-professional-tenant/">“professional tenants”</a> who are skilled at gaming the system by manipulating the rental laws to their advantage, causing their property owners and managers a great deal of grief and monetary loss.</p>

<p>For example, if you don't have a current, written lease, how can you prove the terms of the tenancy should you wind up in a legal battle? Unsavory tenants have been known to make wild claims against unsuspecting landlords in order to skip out on their rent, avoid paying for damages, or worse yet, to make a financial claim for damages against their landlord. A current rental agreement protects landlords and tenants by ensuring that all the terms of the tenancy are in writing. Everything related to the tenancy (particularly the financial details) should be covered in a lease or separate rider/addendum, such as the pet policy, amount and due date of rent and details about the security deposit and future rent increases.</p>

<p>By keeping up-to-date rental agreements and leases on file for all your rental properties, you can set expectations with your tenants, protect yourself and your business in the event that something goes wrong, and reduce your chances of falling victim to scams.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why to Rent Out Your 'For Sale' Home]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rentobo.com/blog/Why-to-rent-out-your-for-sale-home/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-26T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rentobo.com/blog/Why-to-rent-out-your-for-sale-home</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Selling your home is an important decision that should be evaluated carefully in the context of your personal and familial financial situation and needs.  While there are many factors as to why someone would sell, the current robust rental climate can spell opportunity for the right potential landlord. Here are some reasons why renting your home---even temporarily---could be the right move.</p>

<h3>Cover costs while the housing market rebounds</h3>

<p>If you need to sell your home but you aren’t getting the price you want, you might want to wait a year or two. Having a quality tenant in the meantime can help you bridge the gap. To do this, first calculate the costs of keeping and maintaining your home while it is vacant. There can be some additional costs associated with being a landlord (taxes, general maintenance repairs, etc.) so be sure to include those expenses as well. Next, get a sense of what the going rate is for similar rentals in your area---you might be surprised by the results. If the difference in costs are justifiable, go for it!</p>

<h3>You can take advantage of both markets</h3>

<p>According to a <a href="http://http://trends.truliablog.com/vis/rentvsbuy-spr2012/">2012 report based on Trulia’s Buy vs. Rent index</a>, it is cheaper to buy than rent in 98 of the 100 largest metro areas in the country. Chances are that you live in an area where you can take advantage of this. Here’s how: maximize the monthly cash flow coming into your household by securing a tenant at a monthly rate that would surpass your current mortgage. Whether you are downsizing, upgrading or making a parallel switch to a different area, your monthly mortgage cost will likely be less than the monthly rent amount for a similar property. In other words, <em>you are getting the best for your money at both ends of the spectrum</em>.</p>

<h3>You can avoid foreclosure</h3>

<p>The sad truth is that a good amount of families will list their home in order to avoid foreclosure. What’s worse is that a portion of these same families are underwater in their mortgages. However, for some of these people, and maybe you, having a tenant might save you from foreclosure. While it can be difficult to downsize by <em>buying</em> another house (especially with an underwater mortgage,) you can scout for a lease of your own and slash your monthly housing payment. Meanwhile, you can lease your home to a tenant that can pay a premium that will cover most, if not all, your mortgage payment. This is a savvy method of keeping a house that you may not currently be able to afford, and many real estate brokers will recommend this exact move.</p>

<p>As always, there are many factors to consider before becoming a landlord. Before making any decision like this, it is important to fully understand the implications (taxes, lifestyle, and time) of each option. If you do choose to make the leap -- keep <a href="http://www.rentobo.com">Rentobo</a> bookmarked as the easiest way to find your tenant and manage your new rental property.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
